<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Samyak Sarnayak</title><link>https://samyaks.xyz/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Samyak Sarnayak</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 18:35:15 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samyaks.xyz/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Turns out that BFS is not the same as topological sort</title><link>https://samyaks.xyz/post/bfs-topo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 20:51:42 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://samyaks.xyz/post/bfs-topo/</guid><description>The title may seem very obvious to people who know graph algorithms. Unfortunately, I&amp;rsquo;m not one of them.
The problem # This is about implementing a dependency graph. Think of a project&amp;rsquo;s npm/pip/maven/cargo dependencies. Or a data pipeline with SQL tables depending on each other.
Here is the problem that needed to be solved. Given a project or a table (a &amp;ldquo;node&amp;rdquo;) in the tree, how do I get all the other nodes that depend on it (the dependents)?</description></item><item><title>Thoughts on migrating DNS from Netlify to Cloudflare</title><link>https://samyaks.xyz/post/netlify-cloudflare/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 19:07:07 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://samyaks.xyz/post/netlify-cloudflare/</guid><description>Recently, I was involved in the migration of a domain from Netlify DNS to Cloudflare. This short post describes my experiences and thoughts on it.
Why Cloudflare? # We were moving our static sites away from Netlify anyway and it did not make sense to keep it just for the basic DNS it provides.
Also because Cloudflare provides an easy to set up CDN and a reverse proxy.
Why not Route53?</description></item><item><title>Mob Programming and Rust</title><link>https://samyaks.xyz/post/mob/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 16:30:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://samyaks.xyz/post/mob/</guid><description>Have you ever wanted to just think about what needs to be done and the code for it automagically gets written? Well, I have. In its ideal form, this is what pair/mob programming would do — the navigator(s) simply think about and express their idea of what needs to happen and the driver magically gets it done. In the real world though, this does not happen.</description></item><item><title>Hello there!</title><link>https://samyaks.xyz/post/first/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 23:36:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://samyaks.xyz/post/first/</guid><description>Welcome to my blog</description></item><item><title>On water and systems</title><link>https://samyaks.xyz/post/water-docker/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samyaks.xyz/post/water-docker/</guid><description>or how docker is a plumbing system</description></item><item><title>Solving A Git Murder Mystery</title><link>https://samyaks.xyz/post/gitstery/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samyaks.xyz/post/gitstery/</guid><description>gitstery is a murder mystery game entirely contained in a git repo!</description></item><item><title>My old games</title><link>https://samyaks.xyz/post/my-old-games/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samyaks.xyz/post/my-old-games/</guid><description>&lt;p>When I was in school, about 6-7 years ago, I had found a new hobby and passion - making games.
I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how but I found a free 3D game maker named &lt;a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20150514120532/http://www.3drad.com/">&lt;strong>3D Rad&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>.
I played around a lot with it on my ancient PC, which had a Pentium 4 and 1 Gigabyte of RAM.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multiplanetary civilisation?</title><link>https://samyaks.xyz/post/multiplanetary/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samyaks.xyz/post/multiplanetary/</guid><description>Elon Musk recently tweeted about the logistics requirements for a Multiplanetary civilisation. He says that at a minimum, megatons of equipment and other resources have to be put in orbit every year. For reference, a Saturn V (the launch vehicle used to send humans to the moon), can take a payload of around 140 tons to Low Earth Orbit. A launch of Saturn V costs $1.23 billion (in 2019 value). To reach the goal of a megaton per year there would have to be more than 7000 launches per year, or 20 launches per day!</description></item></channel></rss>